womensprosoccer.com 2008-12-18

# Women's Professional Soccer - home of pro soccer players :: Privacy Statement

**PRIVACY POLICY**

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) governs the privacy practices of Women’s Soccer, LLC (“WSL”) and the member teams of Women’s Professional Soccer (“WPS”) (collectively, the “WPS Parties,” “us,” “our,” and “we”) regarding the Official Website of WPS and each of the websites of the WPS member teams (each, a “Website,” and collectively, the “Websites”), including your use of and access to any of the services, features and content on the Websites. We are committed to protecting your privacy. Please read carefully the following description of our policies and practices regarding your personal information before using or accessing the Websites. By using and/or accessing our Websites, you signify your agreement to this Privacy Policy, including but not limited to, the collection and use of your personal information as outlined in this Privacy Policy. Capitalized terms used in this Privacy Policy that are not otherwise defined herein shall have the meanings ascribed to such terms in the Terms of Service available at http://www.womensprosoccer.com/soccer_ektid128.aspx.

**Information Collection**

Your use of the Websites does not necessarily require any disclosure of your personal information. However, in a number of situations, the WPS Parties and their agents and representatives may collect personal information from you. For example, some services, such as our eNewsletter League Insider, promotional contests, Premium Services, fantasy or other games or surveys, and your registration with us, may require you to share personal information about yourself, including your name, street, city and state address, zip code, e-mail address, home and/or mobile phone number(s), date of birth and/or your favorite WPS member team or member team players. We or a designated third party may collect payment and credit card information when you visit the Official WPS League Store (the “Store”) and in connection with processing Premium Services transactions or other transactions at the Store. The third party operator of the Store (not the WPS Parties) is responsible for such third party operator’s collection, use and protection of your information. Additionally, certain third parties (such as companies that run fantasy games on the Websites or advertising companies) may collect personal information from you and share some of the personal information with us. Additional information about the privacy practices of the companies who collect the data will be provided, including how to opt-out of having these companies use your personal information for purposes unrelated to the services that you have requested. Users can find these options on the websites of the relevant third party operator(s). These companies and not the WPS Parties are responsible for the collection and use of your information by these companies. Access to some services may also require you to use a user name and password, established by you. Additional information about you may be revealed in any communications you post on the message boards, which are publicly available to others. We are not responsible for any communications you or a third party post on the message boards. We may collect personal information as required or permitted by law, or with your consent. You may withdraw your consent at any time upon reasonable notice, subject to contractual and legal restrictions, but if you do so, we may not be able to provide some of our services.

**Cookies.** To help us serve you better, from time to time, we or our third party service providers or our marketing partners and advertisers may collect information that does not personally identify you, but identifies your computer or browser through the use of “cookies.” A cookie is a file written to your computer's hard drive that records technical information about your Internet usage, including your IP address, browser type and version, operating system, platform and domain name. Cookies also allow us to keep track of your personal information so that you will not need to re-enter this information during subsequent visits. We may also allow other companies that are advertising or providing services on our Websites to use cookies. This Privacy Policy does not cover those companies' use of cookies. You may refuse cookies by changing your Internet browser preferences, but if you do so, your experience on the Websites may be diminished.

**Widgets.** You may have the option of downloading and installing “widgets” on your desktop, permitted websites and/or your mobile phone. Widgets are mini-applications programmed to perform a specific function or task that may run on your desktop or may be embedded in websites. For example, we may offer you widgets that countdown the time remaining before the kickoff of the league. The widgets we offer that are downloaded or installed by you may require you to input personal information, depending on the widget’s function, and may be able to access or use personal information provided by you. Widgets may (i) check for updates automatically and transmit your information to its server and/or engine; (ii) send information entered into or accessed by the widget to its server and/or engine, which may be stored for a temporary period of time; and (iii) be visible to the public if embedded on publicly available webpages (such as social networking webpages), depending on the policies of that website.

**Opt-in.** Our registration and order forms allow you to indicate whether or not you would like to receive special offers and promotions from us and our partners. Unless you consent to allow us to use your personal information for these offers, we and our partners, and our and their agents and representatives, will only use it to complete the registration or order or provide the service or product requested. If you initially consent to receive such offers, but later change your mind, you can adjust your preferences.

**Third-Party Links.** The Websites may contain links to other websites operated by unrelated third parties. When you click on these links, you will leave our Websites. The privacy practices of third party websites are not our responsibility. Please read the privacy policies of any website that collects personally identifiable information from you. This Privacy Policy applies only to our Websites.

**Information use**

We may use your personal information to communicate with you regarding the Websites, purchases, disputes, payments or inquiries submitted by you. Any personal information submitted to us, or our third party service providers or our marketing partners and advertisers acting on our behalf, will not be sold, leased or shared with or to anyone else by us, unless we notify you otherwise in advance, except as follows:

(1) We may share your information with our third party service providers or our marketing partners or advertisers, to the extent that they may provide the services you have requested.

(2) We may share your information with our affiliates or with any WPS member team’s respective members, affiliates, employees, directors and officers, to the extent that your submitted information relates specifically to such team.

(3) From time to time, we may offer special promotions (such as a contest or a free subscription to goods and services) on the Websites in association with a third party service provider, sponsor or promotional partner. With your consent, we may share your information with that third party service provider, sponsor or promotional partner so that it can offer you other special promotions.

(4) If any of the WPS Parties is sold, your information may be part of the business assets we transfer. Your information also may be disclosed if a WPS Party is considering or completes the financing, securitization, insuring, sale, assignment or other transfer of all or part of such WPS Party.

(5) We may disclose your information to comply with any judicial or governmental subpoenas, warrants or orders. We reserve the right to use, disclose and share your information to investigate, prevent or take action with respect to any potential or actual fraud, illegal activities, circumstances which threaten the physical safety of any person, violations of this Website's Terms of Service or as otherwise required by law.

We may share aggregated demographic information with third parties. Such information does not contain any personal information which may individually identify any person.

We may also use IP addresses for administrative and statistical purposes in order to further understand how people use our Websites and to gather demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are only associated with personally identifiable information when it is necessary to verify users' locations with respect to blackout restrictions for audio and/or video subscription products, as applicable.

**Security**

We employ certain security measures to prevent the unauthorized access, disclosure, loss or destruction of personal information, such as passwords and SSL encryption. However, we cannot guarantee that the information we have gathered will never be accessed, disclosed, lost or destroyed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

**Reviewing Your Personal Information**

You may revise your preferences or amend your personal information by logging onto your account. If you want to close your account and have us delete the personal information in it (except for information kept for record-keeping purposes), please contact us at legal@womensprosoccer.com or by postal mail to:

Women’s Soccer, LLC  
1000 Brannan St.; Suite 401  
San Francisco, CA 94103

**CHILDREN’S PRIVACY STATEMENT**   **(users under 13 years old)**

Federal law prohibits us from collecting any personal information from a child under the age of thirteen without the consent of a parent. (For purposes of this Children’s Privacy Statement, the term “parent” shall be deemed to include a child’s legal guardian). The statements made in this Privacy Policy apply to the personal information of children under the age of thirteen, along with the following additional restrictions.

**Parental Consent.** Some services on the Websites may not be available to children. For services that are available to children under the age of thirteen, during the registration process, if applicable, a screen will appear instructing the child to have a parent complete the registration process, either in person or by e-mail. We will provide the parent with a statement of our privacy practices and will require parental consent for the collection and use of their child’s personal information. The parent may also be asked to submit a credit card number (the card will not be charged) for verification purposes only.

If the registration form is not completed with a credit card number to verify parental consent, the child will not be able to access those of our activities requiring registration and we will not collect any personal information from that child. If registration is incomplete, the child will not be able to post messages or otherwise make personal information available to the public on the Websites. A child's parent may consent to the collection and use of their child's personal information, but may withhold consent regarding the disclosure of that information to third parties. However, if such disclosure is necessary to make available a service which has been requested, then that service will not be available to the child.

**Information Collected.** Depending on the particular service requested, we may collect the child’s name, e-mail address, street, city and state address, zip code and/or date of birth. Only the information that is reasonably necessary for participation in any activity on the Websites is required in order for a child to participate in that activity. A parent can review his or her child's personal information by accessing the child's account. A parent can instruct us to delete or terminate collection or use of a child's personal information by contacting us at [legal@womensprosoccer.com](mailto:legal@womensprosoccer.com).

**Information Use.** A child’s personal information may be used to provide the particular services requested, to fulfill a transaction, for record-keeping purposes, or to market to the child with a parent’s consent, and may be made publicly available through a message board if the child or parent posts such content to the message board. (Please note that any communications made by any person on a message board on the Websites may be publicly available to others.)

**Information Disclosure.** After obtaining parental consent, we, our service providers and one or more WPS member teams (to the extent that any information disclosed is specific to them), will protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of the child’s personal information. A child's information will be shared with our third party service providers or our marketing partners or advertisers and the applicable member team(s) only as permitted in this Privacy Policy. They cannot use your child's personal information without your consent for any purpose other than the service you have requested on behalf of your child.

**Contests and Promotions.** If we offer children under the age of 13 the chance to enter contests and promotions, we will require the child to only submit his or her e-mail address, along with his or her parent’s e-mail address. We will then e-mail the parent to inform him or her that the child has registered for a contest or promotion and to provide information and instructions about the contest or promotion, including how to further register for the promotion, if required, or remove the child from such contest or promotion. The child’s e-mail address is only used to notify him or her if he or she has won. Both the child and the parent will be notified and the parent must provide any further information required to receive the prize. Information collected during the contest or promotion will be removed, deleted and/or destroyed upon completion of the contest or promotion, except to the extent required by law. If a contest or promotion requires other personal information, children will only be allowed to enter by submitting a paper entry form, signed by their parents, and mailed or faxed to us or by the parents submitting additional information online.

**CHILDREN BETWEEN THE AGES OF 13 AND 18**

We recommend that minors who are 13 through 18 years of age seek parental permission before sending information about themselves to anyone over the Internet.

**California Privacy Rights**

If you are a resident of the State of California, under the California Civil Code, you have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed personal information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, a company need only provide you with information on how to exercise your rights if it has a privacy policy that allows you to opt-in or opt-out of the use of your personal information by third parties for marketing purposes.

The WPS Parties have elected the latter option; this comprehensive Privacy Policy provides you with details on how to opt-in or opt-out of the use of your personal information by third parties for direct marketing purposes. Therefore, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of all third parties to which we have disclosed your personal information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes.

If you are a California resident and would like to request information about exercising your third party disclosure rights, please send a request to the following address, and whether you would prefer our response to be sent by e-mail or postal mail. Please send any requests to legal@womensprosoccer.com or by postal mail to:

Women’s Soccer, LLC  
1000 Brannan St.; Suite 401  
San Francisco, CA 94103

For all requests sent by postal mail, please label the envelope or postcard and state on the actual request, “Your California Privacy Rights.” Please include your name, street address (unless you request a response by e-mail), city, state and zip code (for our own record-keeping purposes). We will not accept requests by telephone or fax. We are not responsible for notices labeled or sent improperly, or which contain incomplete information. 

**Notification of Changes**

This Privacy Policy may be amended or modified at the sole discretion of the WPS Parties and new conditions may be imposed at any time without notice. Any such changes or additions will be reflected in an update of this posting. Notices of changes to the Privacy Policy may be generally displayed on the Websites. Please check the Privacy Policy periodically for changes. Your continued use or access to the Websites following the posting of these changes to the Privacy Policy signifies your agreement with those changes. All such changes are hereby incorporated by reference into the Privacy Policy.

**CHOICE OF LAW**

Any disputes arising between you and the WPS Parties regarding this Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of the State of California without regard to its conflict of law provisions. You and the WPS Parties agree to submit to the personal and exclusive jurisdiction of the courts located within the county of San Francisco, California. You hereby waive any argument that any such court does not have jurisdiction over you or that such dispute or venue in any such court is not appropriate or convenient. The WPS Parties will be entitled to recover its court costs and reasonable attorneys’ fees and expenses incurred if it successfully proves your violation of any term of this Privacy Policy.

**Contact Us**

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us at:

Women’s Soccer, LLC  
1000 Brannan St.; Suite 401  
San Francisco, CA 94103

OFFICE: (415) 553-4467  
FAX: (415) 553-4459

Or send an e-mail to [legal@womensprosoccer.com](mailto:legal@womensprosoccer.com "legal@womensprosoccer.com").

Last modified and effective date: January 17, 2008.
